

Burak Kanmaz



+90 (538) 778 90 86



burak@kanmaz.net



12 Apr, 1987

Burak, who is married and has two children, has worked professionally on Microsoft technologies for over 15 years. At the same time, he works by following trend technologies regularly and being open to innovations. With his innovative personality, he attaches great importance to quality, performance, and efficiency in all his work. He also applies this working principle in team and project management.

Work Experiences



Software Architect

Freelance December, 2022 -

Works as a software architect at a US company (name confidential due to NDA), contributing to the development and modernization of the company's main product. Responsibilities include designing and implementing integrations such as a Jira Plugin for project management synchronization, a Microsoft Teams App and a Slack App for team notifications, and leading the migration from .NET Framework to .NET 9. Actively utilizes Docker containerization, Open Telemetry for observability, and Linux scripting to enhance automation, deployment, and monitoring processes. Additionally works on artificial intelligence implementations and automation solutions, while continuously supporting the evolution of the product and technical infrastructure.



Head of Technology

Inooster April, 2022 - December, 2022

He was the Head of Technology at Turkey's most significant company that provided gamification solutions. After starting the business, he helped the company expand its gamification experience to various platforms by developing products in Jira. He oversaw and managed the company's five products and more than 20 customer portfolios, products, and technical processes. He also worked with two software teams that were under his supervision.



Team Lead

Antasya *May, 2021 - April, 2022*

As the Team Lead of a seven-person software team, he managed the team's work and communicated with clients. He successfully managed 15 projects for five corporate companies, including three holdings, one bank, and one production facility.

Apart from managing the team, he also took charge of all technical work within the company. He actively managed the company's physical and digital technical assets, coordinated with other teams, and planned for the company's future.

He played a vital role in technical communication with clients and managing these processes during his tenure. He conducted over 75 interviews and helped expand the internal team. His expertise in Jira allowed the company to offer Jira Consulting services to its clients.

Areas of Expertise

Backend Technologies

.NET, Node JS, ASP.NET MVC, C#

Frontend Technologies

React JS, Angular, Bootstrap, Typescript

Mobile Technologies

Flutter, React Native

Data Store/Process Technologies

EF, MSSQL, PL/SQL, PostreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, RabbitMQ, Solr, Elastic Search (ELK)

DevOps Technologies

Windows Server, IIS, Linux, Docker, Azure, Github Actions, AWS, Cloudflare, Firewall

Project Management Technologies

Jira, Confluence, Azure DevOps, Git, TFS, Bitbucket

Administrative Technologies

Microsoft 365, Exchange, Teams, Azure, MPN, Cloudflare

Other

Information Security and Pentest

Information Security

He has been working in information security as a hobby since 2012. He has provided security consultancy and pentest services to many companies during his studies. In addition to information security, he has provided consultation on social engineering, network security, penetration testing, and application security. He has worked with several companies in this regard.















Solutions Architect

Ericsson May, 2017 - Apr, 2021

He began working as a senior software developer on a team of 20 people for Turkcell, Turkey's largest GSM operator. The team was responsible for the call center flow management project.

In October 2017, he was responsible for handling one of the critical modules within the project. During the year he worked in this position, he acted as the contact person with the customer and served as a lead developer.

In October 2018, he was appointed as the Solutions Architect at the head of a team of 15 people, which was formed to maintain and develop Turkcell Global Bilgi's corporate applications. Throughout the process, he was responsible for establishing the team and managing relations with the customer. He provided development and technical support services for over 20 projects with his team.



IT Manager

Istanbul Commodity Exchange 2015 - 2017

He was responsible for managing a team of five people in the information technology department and fulfilling all the software and hardware requirements of the company's 120 employees spread across five locations.

He restructured the network infrastructure, enhancing security and authorization by modifying internet access rules, file shares, and firewalls. Additionally, he optimized user authorizations to ensure maximum security and authorization. Moreover, he implemented a system to monitor, alert, and control all user actions within the network.



IT Manager Assistant

Ankara Sigorta 2014 - 2015

After discovering a security vulnerability on the Ankara Insurance website, he could access all source codes and databases. Upon notifying the company of the vulnerability, he was assigned as the Assistant Manager of the 12-person Information Technology team, responsible for overseeing the software.

His primary focus was addressing performance issues with the recently developed infrastructure using the .NET Framework.



Senior Software Developer

Doğan Gazetecilik 2012 - 2014

He was actively involved in the Live Score project to broadcast the results of various sports games live, focusing on football. The project was developed using ASP.NET MVC on MSSQL. To ensure faster score updates for visitors, he utilized Angular JS and Knockout JS. With the help of NetScaler, he created a system that could handle 65,000 visitors without any performance issues.



Software Developer

Kariyer.net 2012 - 2012



Software Developer

IRM Ajans 2009 - 2012

Awards and Achievements

<u> </u>	Ericsson awarded him a special appreciation award for his productive remote work with his team during the pandemic.	2020
<u>o</u>	He was also recognized as the "MMEA's 2019 Champions Award Winner" by Ericsson.	2019
T	Additionally, he won first place in the international Imagine Cup software competition held by Microsoft in Turkey.	2010
*	He was also selected twice as a Microsoft Student Partner.	2008,
ð	He has authored a book on Windows 7.	2008

Educational Background



Postgraduate Computer Engineering

Istanbul University - Cerrahpasa 2022 -

He has completed the course phase and is working on a thesis on "Security Vulnerability Review of Code Generated with Artificial Intelligence".



Undergraduate Sociology

Istanbul University 2020 -

He has pursued his interest in sociology and psychology by studying sociology through remote education.



Undergraduate Computer Engineering

Istanbul University 2005 - 2010

During his undergraduate studies, the individual served as the computer club president and the department student representative and worked as a department laboratory assistant.